Parents can learn a lot from that. But to me, "adapt all the time" means something deeper, too. We have to break parents out of this straitjacket that the only ideas we can try at home are ones that come from shrinks or self-help gurus or other family experts. The truth is, their ideas are stale, whereas in all these other worlds there are these new ideas to make groups and teams work effectively. Let's just take a few examples. Let's take the biggest issue of all: family dinner. Everybody knows that having family dinner with your children is good for the kids. But for so many of us, it doesn't work in our lives. I met a celebrity chef in New Orleans who said, "No problem, I'll just time-shift family dinner. I'm not home, can't make family dinner? We'll have family breakfast. We'll meet for a bedtime snack. We'll make Sunday meals more important." And the truth is, recent research backs him up. It turns out there's only 10 minutes of productive time in any family meal. The rest of it's taken up with "take your elbows off the table" and "pass the ketchup." You can take that 10 minutes and move it to any part of the day and have the same benefit. So time-shift family dinner. That's adaptability. An environmental psychologist told me, "If you're sitting in a hard chair on a rigid surface, you'll be more rigid. If you're sitting on a cushioned chair, you'll be more open." She told me, "When you're discipling your children, sit in an upright chair with a cushioned surface. The conversation will go better." My wife and I actually moved where we sit for difficult conversations because I was sitting above in the power position. So move where you sit. That's adaptability. The point is there are all these new ideas out there. We've got to hook them up with parents. So plank number one: Adapt all the time. Be flexible, be open-minded, let the best ideas win. Plank number two: Empower your children. Our instinct as parents is to order our kids around. It's easier, and frankly, we're usually right. There's a reason that few systems have been more waterfall over time than the family. But the single biggest lesson we learned is to reverse the waterfall as much as possible. Enlist the children in their own upbringing. Just yesterday, we were having our family meeting, and we had voted to work on overreacting. So we said, "Okay, give us a reward and give us a punishment. Okay?" So one of my daughters threw out, you get five minutes of overreacting time all week. So we kind of liked that. But then her sister started working the system. She said, "Do I get one five-minute overreaction or can I get 10 30-second overreactions?" I loved that. Spend the time however you want. Now give us a punishment. Okay. If we get 15 minutes of overreaction time, that's the limit. Every minute above that, we have to do one pushup. So you see, this is working. Now look, this system isn't lax. There's plenty of parental authority going on. But we're giving them practice becoming independent, which of course is our ultimate goal. Just as I was leaving to come here tonight, one of my daughters started screaming. The other one said, "Overreaction! Overreaction!" and started counting, and within 10 seconds it had ended. To me that is a certified agile miracle. (Laughter) (Applause) And by the way, research backs this up too. Children who plan their own goals, set weekly schedules, evaluate their own work build up their frontal cortex and take more control over their lives. The point is, we have to let our children succeed on their own terms, and yes, on occasion, fail on their own terms. I was talking to Warren Buffett's banker, and he was chiding me for not letting my children make mistakes with their allowance. And I said, "But what if they drive into a ditch?" He said, "It's much better to drive into a ditch with a $6 allowance than a $60,000-a-year salary or a $6 million inheritance." So the bottom line is, empower your children. Plank number three: Tell your story. Adaptability is fine, but we also need bedrock. Jim Collins, the author of "Good To Great," told me that successful human organizations of any kind have two things in common: they preserve the core, they stimulate progress. So agile is great for stimulating progress, but I kept hearing time and again, you need to preserve the core. So how do you do that? Collins coached us on doing something that businesses do, which is define your mission and identify your core values. So he led us through the process of creating a family mission statement. We did the family equivalent of a corporate retreat. We had a pajama party. I made popcorn. Actually, I burned one, so I made two. My wife bought a flip chart. And we had this great conversation, like, what's important to us? What values do we most uphold? And we ended up with 10 statements. We are travelers, not tourists. We don't like dilemmas. We like solutions. Again, research shows that parents should spend less time worrying about what they do wrong and more time focusing on what they do right, worry less about the bad times and build up the good times. This family mission statement is a great way to identify what it is that you do right. A few weeks later, we got a call from the school. One of our daughters had gotten into a spat. And suddenly we were worried, like, do we have a mean girl on our hands? And we didn't really know what to do, so we called her into my office. The family mission statement was on the wall, and my wife said, "So, anything up there seem to apply?" And she kind of looked down the list, and she said, "Bring people together?" Suddenly we had a way into the conversation. Another great way to tell your story is to tell your children where they came from. Researchers at Emory gave children a simple "what do you know" test. Do you know where your grandparents were born? Do you know where your parents went to high school? Do you know anybody in your family who had a difficult situation, an illness, and they overcame it? The children who scored highest on this "do you know" scale had the highest self-esteem and a greater sense they could control their lives. The "do you know" test was the single biggest predictor of emotional health and happiness. As the author of the study told me, children who have a sense of -- they're part of a larger narrative have greater self-confidence. So my final plank is, tell your story. Spend time retelling the story of your family's positive moments and how you overcame the negative ones. If you give children this happy narrative, you give them the tools to make themselves happier. I was a teenager when I first read "Anna Karenina" and its famous opening sentence, "All happy families are alike. Each unhappy family is unhappy in its own way." When I first read that, I thought, "That sentence is inane. Of course all happy families aren't alike." But as I began working on this project, I began changing my mind. Recent scholarship has allowed us, for the first time, to identify the building blocks that successful families have. I've mentioned just three here today: Adapt all the time, empower the children, tell your story. Is it possible, all these years later, to say Tolstoy was right? The answer, I believe, is yes. When Leo Tolstoy was five years old, his brother Nikolay came to him and said he had engraved the secret to universal happiness on a little green stick, which he had hidden in a ravine on the family's estate in Russia. If the stick were ever found, all humankind would be happy. Tolstoy became consumed with that stick, but he never found it. In fact, he asked to be buried in that ravine where he thought it was hidden. He still lies there today, covered in a layer of green grass. That story perfectly captures for me the final lesson that I learned: Happiness is not something we find, it's something we make. Almost anybody who's looked at well-run organizations has come to pretty much the same conclusion. Greatness is not a matter of circumstance. It's a matter of choice. You don't need some grand plan. You don't need a waterfall. You just need to take small steps, accumulate small wins, keep reaching for that green stick. In the end, this may be the greatest lesson of all. What's the secret to a happy family? Try. (Applause)
Los padres pueden aprender mucho de eso. Pero para mí, "Adaptarse todo el tiempo" significa algo más profundo, también. Tenemos que romper esta camisa de fuerza paterna de que las únicas ideas que podemos intentar en casa son las que provienen de psiquiatras o de gurús de la autoayuda o de expertos en familias. La verdad es que sus ideas son obsoletas, considerando que en todos estos otros mundos existen nuevas ideas para hacer que los grupos trabajen eficazmente. Tomemos solo unos ejemplos. Tomemos el mejor momento de todos: la cena familiar. Todo el mundo sabe que cenar en familia con sus hijos es bueno para los niños. Pero para muchos de nosotros, no funciona en nuestras vidas. Conocí a un famoso chef en Nueva Orleans, que dijo: "No hay problema, solo ajustaré la cena familiar. No estoy en casa, ¿no puedo hacer de cenar para mi familia? Hago un desayuno. Nos reunimos para comer algo antes de acostarnos. Hacemos las comidas del domingo más importantes". Y la verdad es que las investigaciones recientes lo respaldan. Resulta que hay solo 10 minutos de tiempo productivo en cualquier comida familiar. El resto es, "no subas los codos a la mesa" y "pásame la salsa de tomate". Se pueden tomar esos 10 minutos y llevarlos a cualquier parte del día y tienen el mismo beneficio. Cambien, entonces, la cena familiar. Eso es adaptabilidad. Un psicólogo ambiental me dijo: "Si estás sentado en una silla dura sobre una superficie rígida, estarás más rígido. Si estás sentado en una silla acolchada, estarás más abierto". Me dijo: "Cuando estés disciplinando a tus hijos, siéntate en una silla vertical con una superficie acolchada. La conversación irá mejor". Mi esposa y yo realmente cambiamos de silla para conversaciones difíciles porque me sentaba en posición de poder. Muévete de donde te sientas. Eso es adaptabilidad. El punto es que hay todas estas ideas nuevas por ahí. Tenemos que enlazarlas con los padres. Así, pilar número uno: adaptarse todo el tiempo. Sea flexible, de mente abierta, deje ganar a las mejores ideas. Pilar número dos: faculte a sus hijos. Nuestro instinto como padres es dar órdenes a nuestros niños. Es más fácil, y francamente, por lo general tenemos la razón. Hay una razón por la que algunos sistemas se orientan hacia el modelo de cascada más que la familia. Pero la lección más grande que aprendimos es revertir ese modelo de cascada tanto como sea posible. Enliste a los niños en su propia educación. Ayer mismo, que íbamos a tener nuestra reunión familiar, habíamos votado todos para hablar acerca de los berrinches. Así que dijimos: "Bueno, dennos una recompensa y un castigo. ¿Bien?" Así que una de mis hijas soltó, nos dan 5 minutos de berrinche a la semana. y como que nos gustó. Pero luego su hermana comenzó a trabajar el sistema. Dijo, "Tengo un berriche de 5 minutos o 10 berrinches de 30 segundos?" Me encantó. Usa el tiempo como quieras. "Ahora dennos un castigo. ¿Está bien?" Si nos pasamos de 15 minutos de berrinche, ese es el límite. Por cada minuto de más, tenemos que hacer una lagartija Ya ven, está funcionando. Vean, este sistema no es laxo. Se está dando un montón de autoridad parental. Pero les estamos dando práctica para volverse independientes, que por supuesto, es nuestra meta final. Justo cuando estaba saliendo para venir esta noche, una de mis hijas comenzó a gritar. La otra dijo: "¡Berrinche! ¡Berrinche!" y comenzó a contar, y a los 10 segundos había terminado. Para mí eso es un milagro Agile certificado. (Risas) (Aplausos) Y por cierto, la investigación respalda esto también. Los niños que planean sus propias metas, establecen horarios semanales, evalúan su propio trabajo, desarrollan su corteza frontal y tienen más control sobre sus vidas. El punto es que debemos dejar que nuestros hijos tengan éxito en sus propios términos, y sí, en ocasiones, fallar en sus propios términos. Hablaba con el banquero Warren Buffett, y me estaba reprendiendo para no dejar que mis hijos cometieran errores con su mesada. Y dije, "Pero ¿qué pasa si la desperdician?" Dijo, "Es mucho mejor desperdiciar una mesada de 6 dólares que un salario anual de 60 000 dólares o una herencia de 6 millones de dólares". Así, la meta final es, facultar a sus hijos. Pilar número tres: contar su historia. La adaptabilidad está bien, pero también necesitamos cimientos. Jim Collins, autor de "Empresas que sobresalen", me dijo que las organizaciones humanas exitosas de cualquier tipo tienen dos cosas en común: conservan el núcleo, estimulan el progreso. Y Agile es ideal para estimular el progreso, pero permanecí escuchando una y otra vez, se necesita preservar el núcleo. ¿Cómo puedes hacerlo? Collins nos entrenó para hacer algo que hacen en los negocios, que es definir su misión e identificar sus valores fundamentales. Así que él nos guió por el proceso de creación de una misión familiar. Hicimos el equivalente familiar de un retiro corporativo. Tuvimos una fiesta de pijamas. Hice palomitas de maíz. En realidad, quemé unas, así que hice dos. Mi esposa compró un rotafolio. Y tuvimos esa gran conversación, como, ¿qué es lo importante para nosotros? ¿Qué valores apreciamos más? Y terminamos con 10 enunciados. Somos viajeros, no turistas. No nos gustan los dilemas. Queremos soluciones. Otra vez, las investigaciones muestran que los padres deben pasar menos tiempo preocupándose por lo que hacen mal y más tiempo concentrándose en lo que hacen bien, preocuparse menos por los malos momentos y construir los buenos momentos. Esa declaración de misión familiar es una gran manera para identificar qué es lo que haces bien. Unas semanas después, recibimos una llamada de la escuela. Una de nuestras hijas había tenido una pelea. Y de repente estábamos preocupados, ¿acaso tenemos a una niña mala en nuestras manos? Y no sabíamos realmente qué hacer, así que la llamamos a mi oficina. La declaración de la misión de la familia estaba en la pared, y mi esposa dijo: "¿Nada de esto parece aplicarse?" Y pasó la mirada por la lista y dijo: "¿Unir a la gente?" De repente teníamos una respuesta en la conversación. Otra gran manera de contar tu historia es decirle a tus hijos de dónde vinieron. Investigadores en Emory le hicieron a los niños una simple prueba llamada: "Qué sabes". ¿Sabes dónde nacieron tus abuelos? ¿Sabes a qué secundaria fueron tus padres? ¿Conoces a alguien en tu familia que haya tenido una situación difícil, una enfermedad, y la haya superado? Los niños que puntearon más alto en esta evaluación tenían la autoestima más alta y una mayor sensación de que podían controlar sus vidas. La prueba de "Qué sabes" fue el predictor más grande de salud emocional y felicidad. Como el autor del estudio me dijo, los niños que tienen un sentido de... que son parte de una narrativa más grande, tienen mayor confianza en sí mismos. Así, mi pilar final es, cuente su historia. Dedique tiempo a volver a contar la historia de los buenos momentos de la familia y de cómo superaron los malos. Si le dan esta feliz narrativa a sus hijos, le darán las herramientas para hacerse más felices. Yo era un adolescente cuando leí por primera vez "Ana Karenina" y su famosa primera frase, "Todas las familias felices son iguales. Cada familia infeliz es infeliz a su manera". Cuando lo leí por primera vez, pensé, "Esa frase es estúpida. Obviamente todas las familias felices no son iguales". Pero cuando comencé a trabajar en este proyecto, empecé a cambiar de idea. Un estudio reciente nos ha permitido, por primera vez, identificar los fundamentos que tienen las familias exitosas. He mencionado aquí solo tres hoy: Adaptarse todo el tiempo, tomar en cuenta a los niños, contar tu historia. ¿Es posible que pasaran tantos años para reconocer que Tolstoi tenía razón? La respuesta, creo, es sí. Cuando León Tolstoi tenía cinco años, su hermano Nicolás le dijo que había grabado el secreto de la felicidad universal en un pequeño palo verde, que había escondido en un barranco en la finca de la familia en Rusia. Si alguna vez se encontraba el palo, toda la humanidad sería feliz. Tolstoi se obsesionó con ese palo, pero nunca lo encontró. De hecho, pidió ser enterrado en ese barranco donde pensó que estaba oculto. Todavía yace allí hoy, cubierto por una capa de hierba verde. Esa historia me atrapó por completo la última lección que aprendí: La felicidad no es algo que encontramos, es algo que hacemos. Casi todo el que ha estudiado las organizaciones bien dirigidas ha llegado más o menos a la misma conclusión. La grandeza no es un asunto de circunstancia. Es una cuestión de elección. No necesitan un gran plan. No necesitan una cascada. Solo tienen que dar pasos pequeños, acumular pequeñas victorias, seguir buscando ese palo verde. Al final, esta puede ser la lección más grande de todas. ¿Cuál es el secreto para una familia feliz? Intentar. (Aplausos)